SHANMUKH GORLE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

FULL STACK | SOLUTIONS ARCHITECT | CLOUD | MOBILE APPLICATION

SUMMARY

Proficient JAVA developer with over 4+ years of experience creating web applications for businesses using advanced frameworks, design patterns, and web services. A year's experience performing the duties of a scrum master and leading a team of 2 developers. A key contributor to all phases of the software development lifecycle.

WORK HISTORY

August 2022 – Present North Carolina Research Center, Kannapolis, NC

Research Assistant / Java Application Developer

- Led the migration project, transitioning the application from Spring to Spring Boot, resulting in a 30% reduction in configuration effort and a 20% increase in developer productivity.
- Examined and notably reduced the search time of an application by over 15%, streamlining the process of uploading mass spectrometry for effective searching and comparison with an existing chemical compound database.

Tech: Spring Framework, Sprint Boot, Java, Python Selenium, JSP, Spring MVC, MySQL. Athenahealth, India

November 2021 – June 2022

Software Development Engineer - 1

- Contributed to the development of a Healthcare Payment Application that facilitated payment processing between US hospitals and insurance companies, while maintaining over 90% code test coverage.
- Led a team of 2 junior developers, fostering a collaborative and high-performing environment through agile practices.
- Organized Scrum events including Daily Stand-ups, Sprint Planning, Sprint Reviews, and Sprint Retrospectives. Devised strategies that achieved a sprint success rate exceeding 95%.

Tech: Spring Boot, Angular 7, React, MySQL, Amazon AWS, Bitbucket, Perforce, Junit.

May 2019 – November 2021

Cognizant, India

Programmer Analyst

- Developed an application for pilots to manage their flights and trips, consistently upholding a code test coverage exceeding 95%.
- Demonstrated expertise by crafting automation scripts using Terraform.
 Notably, over 90% of infrastructure creation was successfully automated, contributing to efficient and consistent processes.
- Actively participated in defect triage sessions, contributing to the efficient identification and prioritization of high-priority issues.
- Took the initiative to swiftly resolved critical defects, ensuring timely fixes.
- Efficiently addressed and resolved challenges in both development and production environments resulting in 5% downtime.

Tech: Angular 7, Spring Boot, Junit, Java, Azure, Terraform, Jenkins, GitHub, MySQL, GitHub Actions.

May 2018 – June 2018

Global Space Technologies, India

Robotic Intern

- Developed and implemented an Arduino-based robot that successfully detected obstacles, followed black lines, and allowed remote control through an Android application, enhancing user experience, and fostering innovation in robotics.
- The company recognized the bot as their 1st prototype.

Tech: Arduino, C++, Android, Java.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Switchrr - A home automation Android application:

Innovated and designed a home automation system using IoT devices and an Android app.
 Engineered a PCB board that leverages an ESP8266 microcontroller, enabling remote ON/OFF operations.

Tech: ESP8266 microcontroller, Arduino IDE, C++, Android, Java, AWS EC2, PCBWAY, JLCPCB, AWS EC2.

+1 (929)-944-5431

<u></u>

gorleshanmukh@gmail.com

Charlotte, NC 28262



@gorleshanmukh

•

shanmukhgorle.dev

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JAVA

• C

Spring Boot

Spring

Angular 2+

NodeJS

MongoDBJavaScript

ReactJS

......

Express

HTML & CSS

MySQL

Bitbucket

ReactJS

Amazon AWS

■ Git

Microsoft Azure

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Computer Science University of North Carolina, Charlotte

(UNCC)

August 2022 – December 2023 Charlotte, NC

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science and Engineering

Kalinga Institute of Industrial Technology May 2015 – May 2019 Odisha, India

AWARDS AND APPRECIATION

- Received the Cognizant Cheers Gold 2021 award for playing a critical role, showcasing exceptional ownership and leadership qualities, and silver award for working as one.
- Achieved the Cognizant Cheers Silver 2020 award achieving a flawless 100% delivery record across every release.
- Attained the designation of Environment Champion through adeptly tackling and resolving challenges within development environments, while consistently maintaining downtime of less than 5% during sprints.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Teamwork
- Creative Thinking
- Avid Learner & Adaptive
- Responsible and Reliable
- Cross Functional Collaboration
- Database Design
- Agile Methodology
- Java Programming & Frameworks
- MEAN/MERN Stack
- Spring MVC